It's time for deprogram. It's Friday,
August 15, 2025. I'm political
cartoonist Ted R. CIA whistleblower John
Kuryaku is over there on the other side
of the screen. And yeah, in response to
the question, will I always be
introducing John that way? Uh yes, until
he tells me to stop. So, uh thanks
everyone for joining us. Uh we are here.
We ha we will officially be here Monday
through Friday every week night five or
week afternoon I don't know what you
would call it 5:00 PM Eastern time uh
starting Monday. So thanks everyone for
liking following uh supporting the show
in every way possible. You guys have
been awesome. Uh we're we're here on
Rumble as well as uh on X Live and we're
also on YouTube. We're going to be on
Pickaxe soon. Um so that'll be cool.
That's a new uh cool place to uh to go
check out as well. Um just a reminder,
if you're not already doing so, please
consider supporting us by going over to
Rumble uh and watching us there just
because financially u it's been a bit of
a strain for the better part of a year
ever since uh Biden's sanctions closed
down our last job and uh we're pretty
broke and we make a lot more money if
you watch the same exact show with the
same exact experience over on Rumble.
Um, I'm monitoring the Rumble FE feed
today. Producer Robbie's out. So, any
deficiencies in answering the Rumble
questions are totally my fault. I take
full responsibility. John's here in New
York. Um, and John, tell us what you're
up to before.
>> I am here at the Hackers
on Planet Earth or Hackers of Planet
Earth um conference. It's at St. John's
University today, tomorrow, and Sunday
in Queens. And I have to tell you, I'm
impressed with the size and scope of
this thing. This first hackers
conference I've ever been to. They have
three different venues going on
constantly. And I mean from from 10:00
a.m. to 1000 p.m. Um, and some of these
some of these rooms hold, you know, 500
600 people. So, there is a lot going on.
I'm going to speak actually, you know
what? I didn't know what I was going to
speak on until about two hours ago and I
read it in the program.
It says uh my
>> my speech is called
>> talk about winging it.
>> I know, right? Both sides of the wire
surveillance, whistleblowing, and
building a cyber peace movement. And uh
yeah, that's what they're calling it.
And on the uh on the other the other
thing, too. Uh, what I'm going to talk
about a lot though is um the Vault 7
revelations and how the CIA and NSA and
DARPA and the FBI and whoever else wants
to, ATF, DEA uh can spy on Americans in
ways that we can't even fathom and then
what we can do to combat that. So, I'm
here with um a company called Ivy Cyber
and
Oh, that's funny. Stevie got an ad about
bras in the middle of me talking on
Rumble. You know what? Listen, lunch
today.
>> And neither of us has boobs.
>> No. And we don't have moves. Thank god.
Lunch today was two bags of Cheetos in
the speakers lounge. So,
>> if that ad makes us $5, I'm happy to use
it for a McDonald's fillet of fish
sandwich.
>> You're probably being The Cheetos sound
like the meals that are being served to
the Russian journalists who are
attending uh the Anchorage Summit. Uh
they're being put off, but I mean
apparently in very kind of squalid
conditions. Not
>> Trump changed that.
>> Oh, did he? Apparently the Russians made
such a st What Ted's talking about is
all the American um um members of the
media got, you know, rooms at the Hilton
and uh all the Russians got CS in the uh
Alaska Airlines hanger. And so
>> that's wrong
>> with little with sheets.
>> It looks like a early COVID ward in
there. That's exactly That's exactly
what it looks like. And so they raised a
stink. Thank you, Marble. Thank you.
They raised a stink saying that this was
a a an affront against them because
they're Russians. That it was done on
purpose. Trump found out about it as
soon as he landed and ordered that they
be put in I don't know some fivestar
hotel someplace. I
>> does Anchorage have a fivestar hotel? I
don't even know.
>> I'm only aware of the Hilton. I've been
to Anchorage once and that's not a
fivear days. It's not five stars. No,
>> no.
>> Although nothing wrong with staying at a
Hilton at all. I've stayed in many and I
hope to stay in many in the future.
Although they got they're getting rid of
room service, which I think is foul. Uh
Marble 455, thank you so much for the 10
bucks regarding spying. Is the FSB
spying in Alaska now, John?
>> Uh yeah, in fact, just by sheer
coincidence, that one time that I went
to uh to Alaska, I was there with Gary
Johnson when he was running for
president in 2016.
Um, I was able to watch from the balcony
of my room at the Hilton,
um, American fighter jets, I believe
they were F-18s, escorting a Russian spy
plane away from from the city that had
that had flown too close.
>> Yeah, agree with Jace. Anchorage is
surprisingly lovely. It really is. And
there's enough to do there for several
days. It I thought it was fun. And I had
a good time. And I went when the weather
was terrible,
>> late October. But I'll tell you,
everywhere you turn your head, all you
see is dozens and dozens of bald eagles.
They're everywhere.
>> Oh, that's cool.
>> Everywhere you turn your head, it's just
bald eagles.
>> When I lived in the Hamptons, there were
a lot of of bald eagles.
>> That's cool. We have a lot of them in in
the DC area now.
>> Um Yeah.
>> Being harassed by crows.
>> When you and I were kids, they were all
dead because of DDT, right? Their eggs
had all fallen apart. So, thank God
that's a something the EPA did. Uh, bald
eagles would be probably extinct now if
>> All right, let's get into it. Lots of
questions in the feed, but we should
just go right into the obviously into
the big news of the day, which is Trump
and Putin are meeting even as we speak
right now in Alaska uh in Anchorage and
uh everyone's all eyes are there. There
was the handshake immediately uh between
the two men. It's destined to be an
iconic photo already. John, right before
I went on the air, you you got you heard
something.
>> Yeah. So, I'm on this um I'm on this
this list serve that used to be of RT
employees
and so they're constantly constantly
exchanging information. And a couple of
them are there in Alaska with um with
Putin. And uh what they're saying is
that coming out of meeting Sergey
Lavrov, the Russian foreign minister
said that at least some sanctions will
be lifted at the end of the meetings.
Not all sanctions. He didn't say which
ones. He said some sanctions will be
lifted. And in the meantime, Trump said
he believes that there will be a
ceasefire by the end of the meetings.
>> And the end of the meeting is it's just
a one-day meeting, right?
>> This is it. It's one day.
>> Do you think everything's already been
negotiated in advance and they're
basically there to dot the eyes and
cross the tees?
>> I do. I do. And the reason I say yes is
because this was supposed to be a Putin
Trump summit. Uh Putin announced I don't
know 12 hours ago that he was coming not
just with Lavrov but with a a
contingency of their most important
diplomats and at the last second
uh Witoff and Rubio joined Trump on Air
Force One and Hegth flew up separately.
>> So all of a sudden this became a very
big deal.
>> Yeah. Rubio was a sort of a lastminute
addition, right?
>> Yes. Um and so I mean my impression was
I mean look obviously we can only read
tea leaves but that's what that's what
we're paid very poorly to do here. Um I
the idea is you know I mean it looks
like initially the details didn't really
basically first there was the decision
to make to have the summit details had
not been worked out and basically the
feeling was these two guys are just
going to get together in a room feel
that it take each other's temperature
and maybe there's they're going to get
together a second time but between that
decision and today obviously there's
been furious communications between
Washington and Moscow and now uh you
know so things are accelerating.
Obviously, there's tremendous desire on
the part of these two men to normalize
relations. At least that seem I mean,
they say Ukraine's the main point. I
kind of think it's not. I think
normalization is the main point.
>> I agree with you, Ted. I I think at
least in the mind of Donald Trump, he
sees Ukraine as a minor irritant here.
>> That there is a bigger picture, at least
as far as the United States is
concerned, and he wants there to be
movement. Alba is pointing out that um
that CIA director Ratcliffe uh is also
there. That would make sense in
in this contemporary setting because
just the last two CIA directors have
been engaged in foreign policy. So
that's an important point.
>> Marble says if they make a deal, they
get to eat at Lober. That's a reference
to uh the Dayton Peace Accord that we
talked about uh you know that resolved
the uh the the Kosovo the conflict. But
that
>> Ted, did you happen to see
>> it's closed is gone.
>> Oh, I didn't know that. Yeah.
>> Did you see the New York Post report
that Hillary Clinton said she would
nominate Trump for the Nobel Peace Prize
if there's a ceasefire?
>> Yeah, but there was a big caveat, right?
She she says as long as Ukraine doesn't
have to give up any territory.
>> Oh, okay. Well, then
>> that's um let's just say the ranks for
the the odds of that are about the odds
of her becoming president.
>> Yeah.
>> Um so yes, so look, so okay, so uh
there's uh Stevie 3011 says, I don't
believe there will be a lasting
ceasefire. A lot of people feel that
way.
>> I think I have to agree.
>> So this is about normalization first and
foremost.
>> And uh so then there's the question of
what does happen? I mean, you know,
obviously we we want this war in Ukraine
to come to an end. Um, as soon as
possible, what happens there? I mean,
does, you know, is there's just are the
French and the Brits and the Germans
just going to throw too many wrenches
into the works on behalf of Zilinsky to
to stop that from happening?
>> Maybe. Um, I I would have to think that
there's got to be something big in this
for Zilinsky. If he's going to be
expected to to give up territory in
perpetuity, he's going to have to get
something really great in return. Now,
Putin made that that kind of random
comment last week that um that all he
wanted was the territory. He didn't say
anything about Ukrainian NATO
membership. So maybe maybe the
conversation is about NATO membership.
>> Uh Lulu is asking, "Is it impossible to
lift sanctions?" Because I don't think
so. Um the sanctions weren't imposed by
Congress, were they?
>> No. No. They were imposed by the
Treasury Department,
>> right? So that's just an executive
order.
>> Yeah.
>> That's a phone call.
>> That's it.
>> Make them go away. It could literally
blink of an eye like
>> Yeah. Just tw and bewitched. Just uh
just wiggle your nose a little bit and
they're gone.
Yeah, agreed.
>> Um, so well, this is just a theoretical
question obviously, but MW Knox says,
"Do you do you think Putin would give up
what he's taken in exchange for the US
leaving NATO?" Maybe,
>> you know, and you have to think about
how many times, three different times
the Russians asked to join NATO in the
1990s.
>> Yeah.
>> Three times. And three times we said we
didn't think that was a very good idea.
And you know, in retrospect,
>> but it's not an anti-Russian club. It's
just a club where all the weapons point
at Russia, right? And Russia's not
invited to join. Exactly. But it's not
an anti-Russian club.
>> And Marble's got a good question here,
Ted. What what agency facilitates such a
conference? Normally an embassy. Without
a doubt. And and let me tell you, there
is so much work involved with a
presidential visit. They don't care who
you are or how important you are or
think you are in an in an embassy. You
drop everything you're doing and you
work on the presidential visit.
>> Something has been done at a military
base, right? So, this is like exactly
like Dayton, which was at Wright
Patterson Air Force Base.
>> That's right. All DoD and And they're
not really used to putting on big events
like this. The saving graces that
>> But they can provide security.
>> Yes,
>> that's the main point here, right?
>> Um John, I have a I have a question for
you. It just occurred to me. So
technically speaking, uh Putin is
subject to an an ICJ
warrant the second that he steps off
that plane in Anchorage. Uh the United
States is supposed to arrest him and uh
and turn him over.
>> Not necessarily because we are not
signitories to the ICJ.
>> But we're sort of if it was someone
else, we probably would, right?
>> Snatch him.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Without a doubt. So, how you know,
do we have to send a letter to the ICJ
or do we just sort of go la, we can't
hear you?
>> Oh, you know what? Maybe we misread
Tom's uh question. Um, it it's the uh
the Ukrainian aid programs, those are
congressionally mandated. Yes.
>> Oh, okay.
>> So, that would that would take
congressional action. And again,
Congress is not in session. So,
>> but for but for sanctions against
Russia, that's
>> that's Treasury Department. Yeah.
Um and I guess you know well the
sanctions that closed like Sputnik and
RT that's was that Treasury also?
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah it sure was. It was I I can tell
you with more specificity too. It was
all about the banks. So
when Treasury first announced sanctions
um they were very very poorly written
full of loopholes. And so what RT did to
pay us was instead of transferring money
from a Russian bank directly into our
checking accounts, they opened a bank
account in Istanbul and they transferred
the money to this Turkish bank and then
the Turkish bank gave us our paychecks.
And that lasted from the invasion, which
was what, February of 22,
>> to October of 24. and then they
tightened them up and we all lost our
jobs.
>> Uh, by the way, over on Rumble, uh, the
we want to thank the Grace Meister is
now a monthly supporter. We really,
really appreciate you. Thank you so much
for for doing that. Uh, question over
from the Rumble feed. Um, I'm putting it
up there from him or her. Uh, I know
John keeps up with multiple Boomer news
sources. I guess we know this person's
age. Do you keep up with more modern
news outlets like Breaking Points with
Crystal Ball and Sager and Jet?
>> I do. I do. I like Crystal Ball. Um I
like the work that she was doing over at
the Hill, too. And uh and they forced
her out over there, but I think she's
she's quite good.
>> Yeah, I do.
>> And she and she has a very lucky name.
Um
>> she has the perfect media name.
>> Yeah. No, it's true. I mean, I would
love to talk to her parents like, "Hey,
good thinking there." You know, the uh
uh you know, it's like I have several
friends who I've met over the years.
Their last name is Smith and their and
their their shitty parents, their rotten
parents named them John. You know, I
mean, if you name Smith
kid named I went to school with a kid
named Pete Moss. The poor kid.
>> I went to school with a girl named Kathy
Gro and her this was during the 70s. She
had one of those monogram sweaters that
said KGB.
You've you've heard the old story about
the the Spinster sisters in Texas. U
their last name was Hog. H O G G and
their parents named them Ima and Ura.
>> Were they Were they fud?
>> No, they were apparently nice, you know,
ladies, but they were saddled with
these.
>> Thank you, Sodom. 2324 for your very
generous donation. uh asking both of us,
should Iran receive a standing ovation
at the general assembly for their
political leadership during the bombing
campaign and what do you think is their
next move? You know, that's a great
question. Um, a lot of people, a lot of
leaders around the world are very
concerned that there will be yet another
um another Israeli attack on
on uh Iran before the end of the month.
>> Yeah. And uh I think that Benjamin
Netanyahu is afraid of being lost in the
in the shuffle. He wants all eyes to be
on him and is willing to actually kill
people. Uh thank you. ICC, not ICJ, is
actually willing to kill people to
remain in the in the global focus. So
I'm I'm actually uh
Jen I I actually worry about that.
>> Michael Michael's asking world speaking
tour happening New Zealand, Canada.
>> Well
to quote um my uh to quote the the
attorney of someone with whom I used to
be very close. I am a latigious prick.
And so and they said that actually in
court. So,
I sold out nine consecutive
>> I can imagine who that was.
>> I sold out nine consecutive events in
Northern Ireland, Ireland, Scotland, and
Northern England. And um and then like
magic overnight
with 57,000
clicks on the buy tickets now button, I
sold seven tickets. Seven tickets. And
so to make a long story short, we were
able to learn that Meta's algorithm just
no longer likes John Kuryaku. And so
they screwed me. So I hired an so of an
attorney who right now represents not
just the governor and the attorney
general of Texas, but 20 of the P. Diddy
accusers.
He took it on what's the what's the
word? Contingency.
>> Contingency. Thank you. He took it on
contingency because he believes that I
got screwed and that we've got a uh
>> it's gonna be hard to prove. You know,
they don't like to reveal their
algorithms. I mean, and they're probably
going to say it's just all politics,
which is why like when Ted Ra posts a a
barn burner of a political cartoon, it
gets one like on Facebook. And you know,
when Ted Ra posts his cat, you know, he
gets thousand.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, I mean, granted, my cat
is cuter than my cartoons, but still,
>> I filed a I filed a lawsuit against Meta
in the Northern District of Texas, and I
was very, very lucky to find an investor
who is putting up his own money out of
his own pocket to get this speaking tour
back on track. We're going to restart it
in January in Seattle, Portland, San
Francisco, Las Vegas, and Salt Lake
City. And so we will get to Australia
and New Zealand. I promise you it's
gonna happen.
>> That's that's very very cool. Oh, this
one's over from uh Rumble again.
>> I look forward to that.
>> Okay.
>> All right. So about we have a lot to
talk about besides this. Is there
anything? Do we want to leave this and
uh move on? I mean I have high hopes. I
mean
>> I have high
>> I'm a perennial optimist.
>> I'm and I'm always overly optimistic and
I get slapped down. Oh, and Nick,
unfortunately, I'm still banned from
Canada as a dangerous national security
criminal, so I apologize, but I'm not
coming to Canada.
>> That's That sucks.
>> Um Um
>> But yeah, I'm I'm I'm
hopeful,
but I don't want to get my hopes up too
high.
>> We'll see.
>> All right, let's let's move on to
something a little more grim than that.
Uh Ice is running wild. Um the uh
Monrovia California city manager says
there was an ice raid at Home Depot.
Where else? Uh a guy ran away. He was
chased by ICE agents. Uh he was running
across the 210 freeway. Got hit by a car
and killed on site. DHS said that they
didn't chase him. I know who I believe.
>> Um and then there's a new Louisiana
lawsuit. You might remember this case um
where uh JLV versus Akuna where ICE
illegally deported two mothers and their
four children who were all US citizens
uh illegally including a 5-year-old kid
uh with stage 4 kidney cancer to
Honduras in April without any due
process, no medical care whatsoever. I
the moms wanted the kids to stay in the
US, but they threatened to take the kids
away under threat of foster care. So, um
now there's a lawsuit. This we're just
collecting these stories right and left
now.
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. There there was a kid in
uh in Northern California yesterday who
was walking his dog. He's just walking
down the street with his dog on a leash.
Oh, right. and a bunch of uh of INS
thugs jump out of a
>> He's a 17-year-old kid.
>> Yeah. And they they snatched him and no
now nobody knows where he is.
>> And apparently here in New York City,
ICE snatched a seven-year-old out of
elementary school.
>> Uh yesterday, it's the first known case
of a child being plucked out of a New
York City public school.
>> Oh my god.
>> Probably not the last. There are schools
now, I saw in Chicago uh yesterday or
the day before, schools that are um
creating safe areas inside the school
where um they're hidden and they're
locked and if there's an immigration
raid on the school, kids can uh can get
to these safe areas and try to sit it
out.
>> That's I mean, okay, so if you get to
the safe area and ICE decides to come to
the safe area, is someone going to shoot
ICE?
Nobody's got the balls to shoot ice.
>> No. But we now have our we have our
first Well, we now have I guess this is
at least two victims, right, who've been
killed. There was the guy who at the
plant in Arkansas, I think it was, who
fell off a fence or fell off a building
while trying to escape from ICE.
>> Yeah.
>> So, um yeah, it's a lopsided death count
so far. It's kind of like the uh you
know those old charts of the Israel
Palestine conflict. Now, you don't even
need to have those charts because it's
just it's just granted. Um, okay. So,
Star Lion saying, "Hollywood's remaking
The Running Man. One of my favorite
stories." And I really didn't like the
execution of the movie at all.
>> But the book, The book was brilliant.
>> The book, The book is great. It's
Stephen King writing as Richard
Bachmann. Um, yeah, it just dawned on me
how this immigration policy is so
similar,
>> but not fictional. Yeah, it is. And, uh,
yeah. Yeah, it is. Um, it's it's just
horrible. So yeah, ISIS is dressing up
in construction outfits now. I mean, I
mean, they're worse than the Gestapo. At
least the Gestapo, you know, they didn't
they they didn't disguise themselves.
They they were exposed, you know, to the
resistance. We knew who they were. Their
faces were exposed. They didn't indulge
in sleazy tactics like jumping out of a
a van, you know, uh, you know, renting a
rider truck or a Penske truck or
whatever and jumping out of the back at
Home Depot. Of course, obviously you
should stay away from Home Depot if
you're undocumented. Hell, if you're
Latino, you should stay away from Home
Depot.
>> Seriously.
>> And and I'll tell you what, I have gone
to Home Depot to hire workers at least a
half a dozen times.
>> And many of them have business cards.
Oh, sure. You know, oh, they they've
they've set up little LLC's.
>> Well, these are hardworking people,
right? That's my beef here, right? Like
I have no problem at all. Take the
gangbangers, take the criminals, take
the felons, you know, hell, it saves us,
it saves us the money to jail them. Take
them away. Send them back to their home
country. You guys be you. But like,
these are, you know, we were told we
were getting rid rid of the worst of the
worst. These are not them. These are
people. These are law-abiding,
hardworking people. I know people will
say, "Okay, they're not law-abiding
because they entered the country
illegally." Actually, a lot of them
entered the country legally. They
followed all of the rules. They did what
they were told and then basically the
rules refugee status the rules like
basically pulled out from under their
feet.
>> Hey, real quickly I want to say in
response to um to Star Lion, uh tour is
also probably unsafe because um they say
the US government runs 51% of exit
nodes. I'm I'm trying very hard this
weekend to learn a lot of these terms
and I'm listening very closely and I
think what you're saying
>> sounds like Bit Torrent, right? I mean,
>> yeah.
>> What you're saying here, Star Lion, is
absolutely true that um it's all about
the exit nodes and the government does
run a majority of the exit nodes and a
lot of
>> that's like a it's a call back to like
how the NSA started domestic stop
spying. It was at the nodes at companies
like AT&T. Right.
>> That's exactly right. It's it's
something that I mean there are a lot of
people here
who you would expect to see it at an
event like this like with really long
beards and really long hair and really
big bellies because they're just on
their computers 20 hours a day and
>> and they're all geniuses.
And this has been probably the
the most driven
topic so far today since 10 o'clock this
morning.
>> Uh yeah. Well, that's I mean it's it's
not surprising because of this, you
know, especially because of there's so
much overt fear of the government. I
mean, there's one thing about Trump that
I really like. I like a bunch of things
about him actually, like the fact that
he's talking to the Russians. Um but uh
you know one of the things I really like
is you know he makes you scared of the
government and we should be scared of
the government. One of the things I
don't like about the back to brunch
Democrats is that when Biden or let's
say Kamla had won you know everyone
would have been like oh everything's
fine and everything was decidedly
unfine.
>> Yeah you can say that again.
>> So saying thank again another incredibly
generous donation. Um hey we're in New
York for the weekend. I mean I'm in New
York all the time. Uh here's my
contribution for the congestion tax and
all the other taxes and tolls. Uh yeah,
thank you. Uh the congestion tax is
lower on the weekend actually.
>> Um
>> Oh, good.
>> But that's appreciated. Um John, I
assume you took the train. Yeah,
>> I took the train and u to try to save
money. I'm staying with a friend, but he
didn't tell me until I was on the train
that he's in New Jersey.
>> Oh, oops.
>> Yeah. And I'm in
>> not so maybe not the best friend.
>> Oh my god.
>> You could have stayed here at Chateau
Rale in Manhattan. Next time.
>> Next time.
>> It's comfortable. It's airond
conditioned.
>> There's no catches. It's it's on the
transit system.
>> Um well, since you're since you we're
talking about unorthodox um uh living
arrangements, I think we should switch
over to America's favorite dog killing
secretary of cabinet secretary,
Christine.
>> I did. I was shocked when you sent me
this. I was shocked.
>> Really?
>> Yeah. Listen, Bowling Air Force Base is
in what Donald Trump would call a [__]
hole area.
>> Thank you, Marble.
Um, yeah, it's it's bad. It's really
bad. It's it's deep in in southeast
Washington. It's along the the uh PTOAC
River, but on the, you know, the
obviously the DC side of the PTOAC
River, there's literally nothing
anywhere around it. Uh, and it's far
from the Department of Homeland
Security.
So,
>> well, so they claim that basically the
Daily News kind of uh sort of sort of
doxed her and showed photos of her uh
living in in at her of her house in
Navyyard District. Um and so anyway,
because they were concerned that she
might be attacked, uh they moved her
over to Quarters One right at JB uh
Anacostia. Um so, and she's
>> gross over there.
>> That's that's the Coast Guard's place.
So, you were shocked by how gross it was
and that she's living there, not by the
fact that she's living for free, which
is expect Oh, yeah. I would expect a
grift from her. Absolutely.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Without a doubt.
>> So, uh, and you know, when she was
apparently when she was governor of
South Dakota, she also kind of was
accused of grifting $68,000 on upgrading
the mansion. I can't imagine the South
Dakota governor's mansion. The one in
Little Rock, Arkansas, is basically like
just a crappy house and $150,000 on
campaign travel. Although, you know,
it's penny antie really. But
>> yeah,
>> but whatever.
>> Yeah, that's right.
>> But she's kind of penny antie.
>> Oh, I like this. Uh Alba, I totally
agree. Um has as as someone who was
married to someone with borderline
personality disorder, I I I agree with
you. Uh yeah, I think Christy Gnome has
it.
>> Yeah, I have to agree. Anybody that can
shoot an an innocent happy little puppy
in the head,
>> right? Because it was troublesome. Yeah.
>> Like that's your job. Train it.
>> Yeah.
Yeah. Hard to train.
>> So So I mean it What do we have here?
The results of uh Oh, yeah. Well, we
should talk about Gaza. We weren't going
to, but we should.
>> May May I interrupt for one second? I I
spoke to Miko Pellet about this
yesterday. I asked him the same question
and um and he said that the Russians
have made a strategic policy decision to
just not get involved with Gaza. And
it's because since the Soviet Union fell
apart, almost 2 million Russian and
Ukrainian Jews have immigrated to
Israel.
And it's just such a can of worms that
the Russians aren't interested in
getting into the middle of it.
>> H
>> Yeah. And I said, "Well, how does this
impact Iran?
>> It's too many moving parts."
>> Yeah.
>> The Russians have a lot to talk to Trump
about without thinking about that.
>> Oh my gosh. Yes.
>> I mean, I would I would be the first to
say you guys shouldn't be talking about
this.
>> I would agree. I agree. I mean, expect
anything from the Russians. And somebody
even before we started the show, Ted,
somebody asked, I'll go back early on um
asked about
>> uh a story that I that I talked about
where the the Saudis had offered to pay
for a port, an airport, an electrical
grid, water dalination plants. When was
that? That was in 1991, the summer of
1991. And the Israelis said absolutely
not.
>> Well, they didn't. Yeah. They don't
>> 36 years later
>> they don't want that at all.
>> Uh that's a good question. Uh the answer
is probably no. Is there a Apac in other
words riac in Russia? No, there isn't.
Although Russia def definitely had
cordial relations with Israel
decades. Yes.
>> Which is surprising when you think about
the fact that so many uh Israelis are
former uh Soviet citizens who fled the
former Soviet Union. That's right. Um,
>> in fact, there are neighborhoods in in
both Tel Aviv and Jerusalem where you
only hear Russian spoken. The signs are
in Russian. The the political ads are in
Russian.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. It's it's heavily Russian.
>> Yeah. Yeah. For sure. So,
>> and Marcel's got a question here. This
is that's the the $64,000 question. What
cards would Russia even have for Gaza
negotiations? None that I can think of.
>> No.
>> Not anymore.
>> No. Not at all. Um well, you know, we
probably should talk a little bit about
uh Israel. There's um this new plan that
uh the E1 settlement plan, for people
who don't know what that is, uh e the
West Bank is divided into districts that
have these acronyms uh like E1 and so
on. And so this one district called E1,
this right-wing uh dude, uh God, uh
Smootrich,
um he introduced a a settlement plan to
introduce more settlements uh into uh
for 3,400 new housing units in a town
called Maala Adum. Um both the UN and
the UK say these settlements are
illegal. Well, they're all illegal. Um
but he's he's brazenly saying that this
is about destroying any possible
two-state solution by splitting up the
West Bank once and for all. The US uh so
the UN uh has issued its latest
statement. They say it's a war crime if
it goes forward. Um that's couldn't be
clearer. The US however is sort of
saying well we're okay with it as long
as it's not destabilizing.
But of course, it's as destabilizing as
destabilizing knows how to be.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I have to agree. I have to
agree. Um I think it it it would be
greatly destabilizing. You know, I
wanted to say something too about um
Well, Les is mentioning it here and um
somebody mentioned it a moment ago. Oh,
MW Knox. Yes, thank you. uh about Tucker
Carlson's interview with this Greek
Orthodox nun in the West Bank. Have you
followed this at all, Ted?
>> No.
>> I wish I could think like Tucker Carlson
thinks I would make so much more money.
>> Um Tucker,
>> course he also inherited all his money.
>> Yeah. Yeah. He inherited the Swanson
frozen foods
>> billions.
>> Yeah.
>> Um so Tucker interviewed this Greek
Orthodox nun in who's lived in the West
Bank.
uh for the last 29 years. Her name is
Mother Agapia Stephanopoulos
>> and she
>> no relationship to George.
>> No, it's a very common name. It it just
means the the daughter of Steven from
the Pelpeneisian Peninsula.
>> Okay.
>> That's what means from the Pelines.
>> Oh, cool.
>> And Houdini is right. They people are
viciously attacking this poor nun led by
Ted Cruz who is quickly becoming one of
the most anti-Christian elected
officials in America.
>> Bizarre
>> because he's shilling for the Zionists.
That's what this is all about. So, um,
so she gave this interview and it was
about what it's like to be a Christian
and a Palestinian in the West Bank and
what the Israeli government does.
Yesterday,
yesterday, the Israeli government seized
all real estate holdings of the Orthodox
Patriarchet of Jerusalem. Now, mind you,
the Orthodox Patriarchet of Jerusalem
was created in the year 465.
>> Doesn't I mean, didn't they own almost
basically a quarter of Jerusalem?
>> Yes.
>> Wow.
>> And they said, "Oh, well, they haven't
paid their taxes, so we're seizing
everything that you've held since the
year 465."
>> I mean, it's kind of like it would be an
act of war if it there was someone who
who would fight it, you know?
Is she George Stephanopoulos's sister?
Is that what you said?
Um, you know what? I'll look I honestly
George Stephanopoulos's father baptized
me when I was six weeks old. Um, he was
our parish priest.
>> I went to college with George.
>> George has always been kind of an
[__] to me.
>> He was an [__] in college, too.
>> Wow. Um, okay, I stand corrected. That's
his sister. Um, I didn't know he had a
sister, to tell you the truth. Anyway,
she goes into detail in this in this
thing
um
about what it's like to live as a
Palestinian Christian. And you know what
it's like? It's the same as living as a
Palestinian Muslim because the Israelis
don't give two shits if you're a
Christian.
>> I have seen the checkpoints um in in old
in the old city. It's amazing. I mean,
actually, you know, I got to tell you,
the way that the Israelis treat people,
>> the what's really surprising is how
little violence and how little
resistance there is on the part of their
victims. Really truly, most people put
up with a lot more than you would think
they would.
>> I'm I'm answering uh Lulu here. She says
they it it's because evangelicals don't
believe Orthodoxy is Christian. And I'm
I'm writing I always get a kick out of
that because we don't believe
evangelical Christians.
>> Well, I mean I mean the the Orthodox the
Orthodox is the Orthodox dudes were
there first, right? I mean it's like
well the evangelicals don't believe that
Catholics are Christian. Correct.
>> It's kind of like well but Catholics are
OG.
>> Yeah. The Catholics and the Orthodox
>> and the Coptics
>> were and the cops. Yes. We're the
originals.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. It's it's very very strange.
Everyone's always like, "My thing's
real. Your thing's fake." Um so all
right so this this settlement plan I
mean you know obviously the the
settlements are just never going to stop
I I think but in a way yeah so the West
Bank has become because of I mean
obviously the West Bank is the sideshow
in the Middle East conflict. It ought
not to be um the sellers are running
wild. They're they're burning. They're
they're killing and uh and and maming
and raping and burning and torching
Palestinians and their settlements and I
mean in their not their settlements,
their towns um and their ancestral homes
and destroying their crops. Um and it
would be front and center if not for the
bloodshed in Gaza is so much more
severe. The Israeli settlers are just
taking advantage of the fact that all
eyes are on Gaza.
>> Yeah. You know, I read something too uh
just the other day. Uh you know,
remember you and I were um you and I
were talking about um
um Oh, dog gone it. No, I I'll come back
to it now. I have a mental blank. I I'll
think of it.
>> Okay. So, this is interesting. We'll
have to look into this. I'll ask
producer Robbie about this uh when he
gets back. So, the ads on Rumble don't
buffer the live content and resume
later, but essentially skip over it.
After all, both YouTube and Rumble are
still in sync. Well, a couple seconds
apart. That's weird.
>> That is weird.
>> All right. Well, we'll look into that.
Um, but thanks for, you know, these are
growing pains on this show. Uh, we'll
figure it out. Um,
>> yeah.
>> All right. Talking about Sideshow Bob.
>> I call I called him Sideshow Bob this
morning in a conversation I was having.
>> Well, it's so it's so easy. He's uh he's
back and dissing Joe Reagan. All right.
Well, you know, there's that. Um yeah,
this is kind of true. All eyes are on
Russia, so Gaza is in trouble until it's
over. And Gaza is in trouble anyway. Um
I still think this is going to play out
in the end. You know, someone asked when
will it end? I mean, obviously, nobody
knows, but my guess is it's going to be
an East Teeour situation. Uh the
Palestinians will get their freedom,
>> but there will be half of them will be
left.
>> Yeah,
>> that's that's what will happen. I I
agree with you.
>> Um I mean that's the optimistic
>> view as as sick as it is to say that.
>> Yes, indeed.
>> John, let me ask skip to something fun
before we go to something serious.
>> Uh in front of the your old your old job
there in Langley, there is a statue um
that's been up there for I guess 35
years or so. It's called the crypto.
>> I was there at the unveiling.
>> Oh, really?
>> In 1990. So uh so Jim Sandborn is the
sculptor uh and basically there's four
panels on it as I understand it and they
are all code and people have figured out
the have they have decrypted the first
three but the fourth one's never been
solved. It's like one of those classic
uh math problem uh you know math
problems. And um so finally Jim Sandborn
was tired of being asked over and over
and over about it and he's like okay I'm
going to auction off not the statue. I
thought when I first read this that the
sculpture itself was going to be
auctioned but it's going to stay put.
But he's expecting between three and
$500,000 at auction for the solution to
the K4 panel.
>> Um did you ever try to to to work on it?
I would look at that dogone thing every
single day for almost 15 years. So, it's
it's shaped in an S like sitting on its
side
and all through it. It's there are
letters punched in the entire thing and
the letters the word cryptos uh repeats
itself like a hundred times. Kryptos,
cryptos, kryptos. It's everywhere and
then there are other letters
interspersed in between the words
cryptos and then that's it. So there's
some message embedded in there. And when
I was there in the 90s,
um there was an attempt to to load the
information into a Cray computer and
have the computer crack the code and it
just couldn't crack the code.
>> Wow.
>> How's that even possible? So for a while
for for a long while
uh you know these codereakers from NSA
and CIA have have worked to try to
decipher
what it says and the the artist has
never revealed what the message is.
>> I mean you know the NSA right their
headquarters in Fort me is known as the
puzzle palace. Isn't code really I
always assumed coding was more their
perview.
>> It's all it's all their thing. Yeah.
It's
>> like if CIA So CIA had a problem, they
could contact their their colleagues
over at NSA and say, "Hey, can you look
at this?" And Yeah.
>> Yeah. Um it is their thing, but the CIA
the CIA cracked uh the N the OSS cracked
the Nazi codes along with the the
British uh MI6,
>> like the Enigma machine and all that.
>> Yeah, the Enigma machine.
>> That's a cool machine. They've got one
on display in the in the CIA museum on
the first floor. Um, but you're right,
deciphering code is really 99% NSA's
Bailey Wick.
>> So, what's the So, what was the You were
there for the unveiling. I mean, what
was how did they explain like why, you
know, the the the artistic reason that
they put that statue there? Just because
it would be fun.
>> Yeah, they had just built the new
headquarters building a year and a half
earlier. um old headquarters wasn't big
enough and so they more than doubled the
size of CIA headquarters and uh you know
they planted some shrubs and they were
looking for public art. They thought it
would be kind of you know tongue and
cheek and so uh and so they they did it.
>> Uh that's pretty I I agree with this.
This is my kind of thing. What if it was
all a prank, right?
>> And that's why the computer couldn't
break it. But I I guess for three to
$500,000, we're gonna find out. Unless
it's uh you know like that like that uh
who's the like that Banksy thing that
self-destructed at auction.
>> Loved it.
>> Fantastic.
>> Brilliant. Uh and uh Starline points out
correctly that Vault 7 revealed that the
the CIA in many of these areas is going
it alone. Listen, when you've got a
budget that is literally unlimited
and you are unaccountable to anybody
visav what you spend the money on sure
why not duplicate what everybody else is
doing
you expand how many how many
intelligence agencies are there 14 or
16?
>> Uh no it's uh 18 now.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. And there's all these agencies
that like most Americans never ever hear
about like right like the MAPS agency
and
all these DIA nobody ever talks about.
>> Well, those poor guys. Yeah. You don't
you don't want to join the DIA.
>> Really? What's wrong with the DIA?
>> That's where that's where that's where
people went when they couldn't make it
into CIA or NSA.
I mean, literally all they do at DIA is
they have these big maps and they just
they just move little models of soldiers
from one area to the other. It's called
the Order of Battle Briefing, which are
they're mindnumbingly boring, and that's
all those guys do.
>> Okay, I got a couple of John questions
here. Is the octopus thing real or just
a conspiracy?
>> I watched it and it's No, it's
>> it's [__]
>> Yeah.
>> Uh, okay. And then my uh oh this is I
know the answer to this one without
asking. Did you travel first class since
they have an unlimited budget?
>> Business class 72 countries.
>> Yes. The the deal is that you can travel
business class if you report to the
office within 24 hours of arrival.
>> Okay. I mean I would think that first
class might attract the wrong kind of
attention too. Business makes sense.
It's right in between.
>> I I've said this many times. This is a
cover problem because CIA people are the
only government employees on diplomatic
passports traveling business class. All
the other people with diplomatic
passports are in cattle class in the
back.
>> So you can immediately spot
>> the CIA people.
>> That's awesome.
>> Bad cover. Very bad.
>> There's some Central Asian stories. Uh
you know you and are you and I are old
stomping grounds. uh un unbeknownst to
each other, we were there at the same
time. I love this story about Bitcoin
mining. So, it turns out that uh you
know, Central Asia has always struck me
as a place where, you know, you can pull
some [__] because nobody's paying
attention and like and there's kind of
almost no government really. I mean,
there's a government, but you know,
they're not really paying that much
attention to you or to their citizens.
Anyway, turns out that there's illegal I
didn't even know you could do this.
There's illegal Bitcoin mining in
Central Asia. And basically what that
means is the whole theory of Bitcoin
which I think is [__] up beyond belief
is that you know you can mine more bit m
uh you can you can mine it and create it
yourself with your own computers working
at all the time and basically the limit
the in so the intrinsic limitation is
the amount of power that it uses. So
therefore you have to make it use a lot
of power. So literally it's kind of like
a big [__] you to the environment and um
like inherently right no matter even if
you think Bitcoin is a great idea I'm
not even going to get into whether I
believe in it or not that's you know
subjective and what I think about that
doesn't matter but the environmental
thing is ridiculous but anyway in
Tajikhstan
um people uh the lo local the local uh
rogues um stole three and a half million
dollars from sto in stolen electricity
in the first quarter of this year alone.
Tajjikstan is a you know well it is a
less poor than it used to be but still
the poorest country in the former Soviet
Union. Um so that's a lot of that's a
lot. Um they've charged 100 there's 190
cases involving almost 4,000 people that
the Tajik authorities have caught doing
this. Um meanwhile, the Kazaks found a
16.5 million dollar scheme involving 50
megawws. Um you linked to uh Russian and
Chinese miners exploiting weak
oversight. Um so basically, you know,
you look at the location, right?
Tajikistan borders China, Kazakhstan
also borders China and uh also Russia.
Um, and so, you know, you can sort of
see like this is kind of like Silk Road
smuggling like the old days, but it's
Bitcoin.
>> I was um also surprised to see this. It
seems to me like it would be hard to
steal electricity and kind of dangerous.
>> Yeah, for sure. Especially at that
level. I mean, you know, things can
explode. Um, you know, I mean, I think
it's like when you see the homeless guy
opening up the bottom of the lamp post
with a screwdriver and like and trying
to run a radio or charge their phone off
of it.
>> Exactly.
>> It's one of the reasons that in New York
they they introduced these like phone
chargers like kiosks on the street for
homeless people so that they wouldn't do
that. Oh, when I was living in New York
in 2002,
um, a whole bunch of dogs were getting
electrocuted because they were peeing on
lampost and the lamposts weren't
properly grounded and they were killing
the dogs.
>> That makes China laugh. That is funny
though.
>> Uh, but can you imagine doing this?
Like, you know, this is like the way
poor people in Nigeria uh smash holes
into the oil pipelines and try to steal
oil and then sell it on the black
market. and um every couple of years
they explode and kill hundreds and
hundreds of people, wipe out entire
villages. It seems like it would be the
same thing. When I was in Hong Kong last
year to go to a Bitcoin conference,
total complete waste of time. Um
one of the present not presenters, one
of the the big um kiosks was sponsored
by the government of uh Bolivia, right?
So, there are 200 little startups that
nobody's ever heard of and then this
giant tent sponsored by the government
of Bolivia because they wanted everybody
to know what cheap electricity they
have. They have solar, they have wind,
they have hydro power. Come and mine
your Bitcoin in Bolivia. And people were
like mobbed into this place like, "Oh,
what a great idea."
It just seems all kind of nuts to me.
>> Yeah, I think it's I think it is
completely insane. What What Why did the
world need new more money
>> or new money or I know it's kind of not
money but it kind of is money.
>> I agree. Uh that yeah, Bitcoin with Tom.
Bitcoin is not a currency. It's a
speculation.
>> We're being asked what are our favorite
stons? In other words, uh Turkmanistan,
Usbekistan, Kyrgystan, Kazakhstan,
Tajikistan. Um, I like them all to be
honest, but I really do. Um, I would say
Usuzbekistan's the most got the most to
do, but
>> and maybe the best food.
>> That might be true. And it has the best
cities and it has a real it has real
cities, including one with a met with a
metro, Tash Kent. But I have to admit,
I'm really really partial to uh
Kyrgystan. Um, the people the people are
great. um they're you know they're they
they are whenever there's a border
dispute in the Central Asian Republic
Kirgeis negotiators are brought in to
settle things because they're widely
accepted as being like wise you know
like basically there's all these
theories
>> about the you know like basically the
central Asians all have different
reputations right like the Tajiks are
reputed to be kind but kind of dim um
the uh Turkmen are kind of thought of as
being kind of dumb Uh the Lisbeks are
aggressive like almost like Americans
like basically you know a little bit
invadey and hostile and bullying. Uh the
Kazaks are are kind of like stick up the
ass like sticklers for the rules.
>> Yeah.
>> Um I remember they they would when you
had to declare every penny that you
entered Kazakhstan, they would make you
count everything out, every bit of
currency. If you were off by a penny,
they'd take it all. If you weren't off
at all, you could have a million
dollars. They'd let you keep it. But you
had to be exactly right. And so I mean
it's but uh you know I mean I do I I
like the Kiergeis. I mean Turk Menistan
is cool and weird. I mean it's got the
best bazaar I've ever been to in my
life.
>> Really?
>> Tolkucha outside of Ashkabbat. Yeah. I
mean best place to buy carpets in the
world without a doubt. And and antiques
and all sorts of other good stuff. Old
Soviet crap. It's great.
>> Oh you you and I should have a
conversation later offline about that.
Okay, let's do that.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Um,
>> I have to say I have not been to as many
as you have, but I'm really really
partial to Pakistan.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> I really am, man. The history and the
food and the landscape.
>> I like the north.
>> Especially in the north.
>> Yeah. where you drive down the road, you
see, you know, cows and horses and and,
you know, whatever, but then you see
wild boores running down the side of the
mountain and then there are there's a
tree full of monkeys
>> and they're like mean hostile monkeys
that
>> and the water buffaloos look out
>> water buffaloos. It's crazy
>> crazy.
>> I mean, yeah, the the the myth of
Shangla, right, is based in uh in
Pakistani Kashmir. And then going over
to the um to the uh the Afghan border up
north at Pashaw for example ever pass.
Oh my god. I've never seen anything like
it.
>> I got Yeah, I got to do that. Uh it was
amazing. There's a there's a train, you
know. There's
>> I want to do the train.
>> A steam a steam engine train.
>> Yes. And the kyber rifles ride on top
like in the old days like you know and
and the thing is apparently full of
dinged with bullet holes because they
get ambushed all the time.
you know, the Kyber Pass is not worried
about worried about getting sick when I
was up there.
>> Well, that's a good concern
>> that and I was really worried about it.
So, I found a uh what's the British uh
it's like the British version of Subway
sandwiches.
>> Oh, Wimpies.
>> Wimpies. Wimpies. Thank you. So, I went
into Wimpies and they had um baloney
and I said, "Uh, yeah, give me a
bologoney and cheese on white bread."
And he's like, "Okay, do you want
tomato?" "Nope."
>> Gross.
>> Lettuce? No. Mayo? No. None of that
stuff
>> just to throw it at a customs and border
for
>> Yeah. And and I would just go back to
the wimpies every day that I was in
Pashawer. You were just trying.
>> I was the only one who didn't get sick
in the end because you ate that.
>> We went to the British uh the officers
club one night for for beers and
everybody got sick there.
>> Oh, no. It's I mean I I have lost so
much weight. Like I'm a little chubby
right now. I could really stand a trip
to Central Asia. The diarrhea diet plan
will will definitely take care of it.
>> I had an oldtime tell me when I first
arrived. I said, "You know, I'm a little
bit worried about getting sick." He
goes, "Oh, you're going to get sick."
Oh, yeah. He said, "Listen, if you just
accept the fact that you're going to get
sick, you're probably going to [__]
yourself at some point, but just don't
tear yourself up about it. Then you're
going to be okay."
>> Yeah. It's just going to happen.
Hydrate.
>> Yeah. Hydrate. I never shot myself, but
I was sick for at least 50% of the time
that I was stationed in Pakistan.
Low-grade fever, cramps.
Yeah. No, I mean the cramps uh the first
time I went to Central Asia, I mean it
was just it's like a knives turning in
your in your stomach over and over and
over.
>> Yep. And then you get the chills in the
middle of the night and oh my god it's
just terrible.
>> Every time you go it's less it's less
bad.
>> Mhm.
>> Although I've gotten giardia a few times
out there.
>> Oh my god. I I was hospitalized in Cairo
with giardia once. Like for death to
liberate me from this thing.
>> And what's really rough is it's in your
system for for the rest of your life.
And whenever your immune system is weak,
it can come back any time, even when
you're eating rice. So,
>> yes. Hey, and and uh What Nonsense is
reminding us very appropriately that we
um we need to remind people to please,
please like and uh subscribe, please. It
helps.
>> Like, follow and share the show. Please,
please, please. I'll put it up again.
>> Share, subscribe, follow, all that
stuff.
>> All right.
I felt so welcomed in Pakistan. I'll
tell you what, I'll tell you two little
things. When I got home, um, I remember
my wife, well, she wasn't my wife then,
and she was my girlfriend, but she woke
me up in the middle of the night. She
said, "You're talking in your sleep."
And to tell you the truth, that's that's
a thing at the agency that if you're
talking in your sleep and you realize it
or someone tells you, you have to report
yourself to security, right? because you
may be talking about classified
programs. So I said I said, "Oh my god,
was I speaking gibberish or did you
understand what I what I said?" And you
said or she said you said you were in
Lahore and you were going out to buy
spices.
>> That was one thing.
>> There goes your clearance suit. And he
says,
>> "Oh my god."
>> Uh any qu any issues with the mosquitoes
in Pakistan?
>> Oh yes yes yes.
They gave us um chloroquinine before we
left um for to fight malaria. I was like
one of the only people that didn't come
back with malaria and that's another
thing that keeps coming back years after
you get it.
>> But um chlorinine gives you such
vicious ferocious nightmares
>> that after three or four
>> Yeah. I three or four nights I was like
I I' I'd rather just risk the malaria.
And so what I did is I kept for for the
whole, you know, eight months that I was
there, I kept the ceiling fan on full
blast just to keep the mosquitoes off of
me.
>> So it was awful.
>> Yeah, mosquitoes are a problem
everywhere in the developing world. Uh
no question about it. Um Central Asia is
not so bad. I mean Pakistan, South Asia,
not Central Asia.
>> South Asia. Yeah. Um but uh yeah, no I
mean it definitely uh you know I I got
to say I had really mixed reviews for
Pakistan. I had some of my best and some
of my worst experiences there. I mean
you know driving down the the street in
a jeep and having little kids throw
rocks at us because you know we're
obviously Americans and you know I think
it's the most anti-American
>> country I've ever been to. Worse than
Afghanistan.
I'm gonna say um
yeah, that's probably true. Yemen's
pretty bad.
>> Oh yeah, I found Yeah. Yeah,
>> I saw that in Yemen, but I didn't
>> Yeah.
>> experience. I wasn't
>> Pakistan and Yemen probably the two most
anti-American um
>> never understood what the why the
Pakistanis got a raise after 911 at all.
Um while we're talking about Central
Asia though, um also uh this just
slipped through the news, right? So I
didn't know that any country had uh
recognized the Taliban government that
took over in the fall of 2021 but they
did. Uh Russia has now u given formal
diplomatic relationships to Taliban. I
mean that's a huge thing not just
because Russia is a massive country but
also considering the history right of
the of the of the Russian war the Soviet
war in in Russia where they got their
asses kicked and handed to them. um you
know so the fact of them doing that is
amazing and then speaking of central
Asia Kazakhstan has recognized a talib
as charge of affairs and Tajjikhstan
which is a neighbor I had a fun
conversation with the minister of
foreign affairs in Duchon Bay in
Tajjikstan and we're talking about
Afghanistan and I said oh what do you
think and he said oh you mean our rowdy
neighbor to the south
[Music]
and it's like that's fair you know this
was in
>> this was in 2001 when he told me that
it's like very rowdy. It's kind of like
these people keep you up all night long.
Um it's like yeah I mean you gota I mean
those it's got to be tough for the to be
like Tajjikstan is really like sort of
they have a lot of people all around
them who kind of like are a pain in the
ass, right?
>> It's a rough neighborhood. That's
>> it is a rough neighborhood.
Um yeah, but the Tajik they their their
only natural resource was really rocks
and ice until recently and then they
they found oil um you know about 10
years ago through deep super deep
drilling. They there's a new technique
where they can go up a mile and a half
down and get the oil and the Tajik are
like hey we have oil too. It's a game
changer.
>> Wow.
>> So
>> which I mean and that's a country also
god that civil war right. I mean the
signs of it are everywhere. You still
see the tanks all over the place. But
like in the 90s, nobody gave any shits
about Tajjikstan while they were
slaughtering each other. I mean it was
brutal there. And uh and basically they
all sides just I I always say this is
like the peace. This is like what peace
looks like. All sides were armed by u
they were all proxies, right? Like there
was a a Taliban proxy, a US proxy, a
Chinese proxy. everybody, all the
foreign powers lost interest, stopped
funding. They they exhausted themselves,
and at a certain point, they signed a
power sharing a agreement, and they were
just like, "Yeah, we're just going to
like have to live with each other and
just rebuild." They never had a
revolution or anything. They never
overthrew President Rakmon. Uh but uh
you know, they they've they've gotten it
together. They've they've turned it
around. I mean, it's a cool place to
see.
>> I'd love to see it. I'd love to. And I'd
love to go to Mongolia.
>> Oh, that's that's my next plan. I want
to go I want to go horse trekking in
Mongolia.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, there's I got an invitation.
>> And there's also that Jewish uh
autonomous oblast in southeastern
Russia. Yes. By the Kazak Mongolian
border.
>> I'm dying to go see that.
>> I um I got a call from Afia Sadiki's
attorney day before yesterday. Afia
Sadiki is a Harvard educated Harvard
medical school educated physician who um
self-radicalized
uh joined al-Qaeda and um fired at
several
uh FBI agents while she was uh being
interrogated. Um she she's been
sentenced to like life without parole,
whatever. Uh and she's been in prison
since 200
seven or eight.
>> And um
and uh word has just gotten out that
when she was arrested
along with her three children, the CIA
took the children
and um and just placed them with
strangers. Well, the two oldest children
made their way back to Afia Sadiki's
sister, who's also a Harvard Medical
School trained urologist. Uh, and these
children are US citizens, by the way.
The youngest was 6 months old. Nobody
ever figured out where she was sent.
Now, here it is 20 years later.
>> Wow.
>> 18 years later, nobody knows where this
child is. So, he's suing the CIA on her
behalf. and he asked me if I would go to
Afghanistan with him
to give a deposition to some United
Nations group that I don't I don't
understand the whole thing. I said, you
know, I'm I'm very uncomfortable going
to Afghanistan because of what I used to
do, but um
but I I would con I would consider it,
>> you know. I mean, my my take on that
would be it would work if you visited an
Afghan consulate first. Um, you know, if
you can find one, maybe the one in
Moscow
>> and just sort of explain the situation
to them and just sort of say like, well,
you know,
>> I mean,
>> Afghans are very reasonable people, but
things have to be explained and and you
know, as you know, a safe conduct piece
of paper will get you out of every
problem.
>> Got that right. So,
>> hey, have we ever considered going to
North Africa? I love North Africa. I've
been many times. It's
>> I've only been to Morocco. I want to do
more.
>> Um, Morocco, Tunisia, Algeria, and I've
been four or five times to Egypt. Really
great.
>> Yeah, North Africa. I'm I'm dying to,
especially because I speak French, you
know. So, Algeria and Tunisia, it' be
super interesting for me. But, I mean,
it's it's North Africa. I'm pissed
honestly at Hillary Clinton because I I
had already studied up about Libya and
the and the Lonely Planet guide. I was
dying to go to Apparently it had like
one of the best bizaars in in the world
also. And you know they [__] Hillary
Clinton and and Barack Obama broke that
country.
>> They did. They broke it. And it's more
than what a decade and a half ago and it
still is is a complete and total
disaster.
>> Yeah. Because of those two [__]
>> Mhm.
Well,
okay, one last official topic and
whatever questions. Uh, so the um
Democrats,
this won't take long. Uh, Democrats in
is uh they are they are introducing
resolutions to end Trump's uh
federalization of the DC police. Uh
they're going after the state of
emergency that he declared and uh
calling out the National Guard. They
there's also some lawsuits that argue
that he's violating Trump that is the
1973 Home Rule Act which restores uh
just like it would sounds uh you know
local rule to DC. Um so Jamie Rascin and
Chris Vonaland are doing this. Um
obviously the Republicans are in charge
of Congress so I'm going to assume
no nothing at all. Right. I mean
nothing's going to happen here.
Uh, no. Nothing's going to happen. And
just as we predicted, just as we
predicted,
the federal law enforcement figures that
the that the White House sent in have
done nothing but write seat belt
tickets, brake light tickets, and
cleaned out the uh homeless encampments.
This has nothing to do with fighting
crime. Nothing.
>> So, where do the homeless go? And and
why are they doing that? Is that's like
a way to sort of get contact and collect
information from DC people? Like, you
know, when you write a ticket to
someone, you get their driver's license
information, you get their data, you
have their body camera.
>> Oh, no. I think they just want to be
dicks to tell you the truth. Uh but in
terms of the of clearing out the
homeless encampments, they're just
there's a there's a law in DC that
you're supposed to give the homeless 14
days notice that you're going to push
them out unless the encampment is along
a highway and then they get 24 hours.
And so the White House is giving them 24
hours no matter where they are. And
they're just pushing them deeper into
the woods in Rock Creek Park. This is
just so tourists won't be able to see
homeless people. That's what it's all
about.
>> Ridiculous.
>> Terrible.
>> So, um, you know, the thing is that as
my friend Scott Stantis likes to say,
uh, Trump has the, uh, has the has has
the attention span of a deranged flea.
So, probably he's going to like forget
all about this in no time. But, it is
terrifying just how everyone puts up
with it. And really, you have to. I
mean, armed men pull you over and you
know, you you're not wearing your
seatelt. Well, you know, I mean, what
can you do?
>> Yeah. Whatever you do, don't throw a
sandwich at the guy.
>> Yeah.
>> 10 years in prison.
>> Certainly not. Um, you know, I mean
Yeah. I mean, obviously those charges
are going to be dropped, right? They'll
be dropped. Oh, yeah.
>> That's what always happens.
>> Always. You know, it's like when when in
New York they go after the mob, right?
They they arrest 20 guys. They make him
do the perp walk. They say they're going
to charge him with RICO predicates.
They're all going to get 50 to life. And
then six months later, very quietly,
they all take a guilty plea to a
gambling charge and get six months.
>> Always. And the protesters, same thing,
right? They cattle them. They treat them
like [__] And then it's like, you know,
oh, you you know, like the rowdy, the
ones at Columbia University and during
the RNC in 2004 and all that.
>> It's always like that. Um, let's see. 31
Arab countries. Well, I don't know what
this means. Tariq will have to tell us.
31 countries issue a joint statement
about greater Israel. All right. Well, I
don't know what that
>> probably probably warning us, which
Americans need to be warned.
>> Yeah. This is
>> Yeah. Well, yeah. Yeah. I mean, the
Israelis have I mean, one of the ways I
can really tell that the Israelis are up
against the ropes and their husband
this week is called In Defense of
October 7th. And I've heard almost
nothing from these [__] So, you can
only imagine, I mean, I'm not saying
they were right to kill civilians and
stuff like that, but basically, you have
to read the column. But that title,
right, it's kind of clickbaity, right?
And you know, it's like I got a few
people who are like, "Well, that's a
provocative column."
I mean, can you imagine writing
something that that a year ago? I mean,
you know, you'd be lucky to have your
head still attached.
>> You got that right.
>> Yeah. So, anyway, uh
>> a busy week and uh yeah, you and I are
going to hang tomorrow. So, we should go
and you should get prepared for your
speech because obviously now that you
know what you're going to talk about,
it's good. You can you can get ready. Uh
John, always a pleasure. Everyone, thank
you so much for joining us here. Uh it's
been a busy week. We will be back Monday
5:00 Eastern time here with DP program
with uh me, Ted R, and John Kiryaku. And
uh we will you can find us online. Uh in
the meantime, you can always uh write to
both John and I through our respective
websites. Just Google them and it'll
it'll come right up. Um please like,
follow, and share the show. And uh see
y'all later.
>> Five days next week.
>> Five days.